后 天
南极洲 拉尔森Ｂ冰架
你看清楚怎么做了吗？
You see how it's done?
是啊 我想我找到窍门了
Yeah, I think I got the hang of it.
你最好能行 如果把冰芯搞砸了老板会把我的脑袋拧下来
You better. The boss will chew my head off if these cores get messed up.
别担心
Don't worry.
我们钻到二十六英尺深了
We're at 26 feet.
你让詹森一个人去操作钻探机？
You let Jason operate the drill?
嗯 他能行的
Yeah, he can handle it.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
把你的手伸给我！ 别管钻探机了！
Give me your hand! Let go of the drill!
别管了 杰克！ 太晚了！
Forget it, Jack! It's too late!
你办不到的！
You're not gonna make it!
杰克！
Jack!
杰克！ 把你的手给我！
Jack! Give me your hand!
我抓到你了！
I've got you!
你刚才在想什么呢？
What were you thinking?
- 这是怎么回事？- 整个冰架裂开了！
- What's happening? - The whole damn shelf is breaking off!
就是这样
That's what's happening!
我们发现了一万年前灾难性的气候迁移的证据
We found evidence of a cataclysmic climate shift, which occurred 10,000 years ago.
新德里 联合国全球气候变暖会议
这些温室效应气体在冰芯中的聚集...
The concentration of these natural greenhouse gases in the ice cores...
显示出气候失控性的变暖把地球推向冰川时代...
...indicates that runaway warming pushed Earth into an ice age...
而这一直持续了两个世纪
...which lasted two centuries.
我被你搞糊涂了
I'm confused.
我还以为你是在讨论全球变暖问题而不是冰川时代
I thought you were talking about global warming, not an ice age.
是 有点自相矛盾 但全球变暖能导致气候冷却趋势 我来解释
Yes, it is a paradox, but global warming can trigger a cooling trend. Let me explain.
北大西洋暖流直接影响北半球气候
The Northern Hemisphere owes its climate to the North Atlantic Current.
来自太阳的热量到达赤道后再由洋流传送到北方
Heat from the sun arrives at the equator and is carried north by the ocean.
但是全球变暖正在融化极地的冰川 而这干扰了这个洋流
But global warming is melting the polar ice caps and disrupting this flow.
最后它会慢慢停下来 到那时候...
Eventually it will shut down. And when that occurs...
我们温暖的天气就消失了
...there goes our warm climate.
对不起 你认为这情形什么时候会发生呢？教授？什么时候？
Excuse me. When do you think this could happen, professor? When?
我不知道 也许一百年 也许一千年 但是我知道...
I don't know. Maybe in 100 years, maybe in 1,000. But what I do know is...
如果我们不很快采取行动 我们的子孙后代会为此付出代价
...that if we do not act soon, our children and grandchildren will have to pay the price.
那谁将会为京都协定书付出代价呢？
And who's going to pay the price of the Kyoto Accord?
世界经济将会为此损失亿万美元
It would cost the world's economy hundreds of billions of dollars.
恕我直言 副总统 如果现在我们不采取行动付出的代价会更高
With all due respect, Mr. Vice President, the cost of doing nothing could be even higher.
我们的气候十分脆弱
Our climate is fragile.
按照我们燃烧原油和污染环境的速度...
At the rate we're burning fossil fuels and polluting the environment...
冰川将会很快消失
...the ice caps will soon disappear.
霍尔教授
Professor Hall...
我们的经济就象环境一样脆弱
...our economy is every bit as fragile as the environment.
也许在做出这种耸人听闻的声明之前 你应该记住这一点
Perhaps you should keep that in mind before making sensationalist claims.
喔 上次断裂的冰块...
Well, the last chunk of ice that broke off...
差不多象罗德岛州那么大
...was about the size of Rhode Island.
有些人可能会觉得这相当的耸人听闻
Some people might call that pretty sensational.
阻止全球变暖！阻止全球变暖！
Stop global warming! Stop global warming!
我现在正在新德里的全球变暖会议场外
I'm at the Global Warming Conference in New Delhi...
这里 难以置信的是 正在下雪
...where, if you can believe it, it's snowing.
有史以来最寒冷的气候给整个城市造成了严重的混乱
The coldest weather on record has thrown the city into chaos...
大量的无家可归者被冻死
...with numbers of homeless people freezing to death.
出租车！
Taxi!
我非常欣赏你的报告 教授 非常有感染力
I enjoyed your testimony, professor. It was very spirited.
喔 谢谢 那正是我们来这里的目的 不是吗？要让大家看看
Oh, thank you. That's what we're here for, right? Put on a good show?
很对 我在想我能不能和你谈谈有关暖流迁移中断的理论呢
Quite. I was wondering if I could talk to you about your theory on abrupt climate shift.
我叫瑞博森 特里·瑞博森
The name's Rapson. Terry Rapson.
- 瑞博森教授？海德兰中心的？- 就是我
- Professor Rapson? Of the Hedland Center? - That's me.
我读过您有关洋流的论文
I've read your work on ocean currents.
- 我们找个地方喝杯茶怎么样？- 非常好 如果能打到车的话
- What do you say to a spot of tea? - Absolutely. If we can hail a cab.
这里
Over here.
欢迎您回来收看 这里是苏格兰格拉斯哥曼彻斯特联队
Welcome back to Glasgow, Scotland, where Manchester United...
在客场以三比一领先凯尔特人队
...Leads 3 - 1 over hometown Celtic.
赫德兰气候观测中心 苏格兰
现在比赛进行到下半时六十三分钟 曼彻斯特联队
We return 63 minutes into the second half as Manchester United...
看起来已经牢牢控制了场上局势 我们来看看我们的评论员
...looks to put the game out of reach. Let's get back to our commentator...
唐纳德·麦克法兰德怎么说？
...Donald MacFarland.
怎么啦？
What? Yeah.
- 我刚刚打了个盹 哥们 - 是
- I just closed my eyes for a sec, man. - Yeah.
小孩折腾了我们一宿
The baby kept us awake all night.
- 进球 - 好！
- And still. - Yeah!
丹尼斯？流浪者型浮标4311号显示温度降低了十三度
Dennis? NOMAD buoy 4311 is showing a temperature drop of 13 degrees.
- 嗯？4311号在哪里？- 喔 在...
- Yeah? Where is 4311? - Well, it's...
乔治海岸 那里是气候恶劣的海域
Georges Bank. It's rough seas out there.
一定是出故障了
Must have knocked it about.
踢那该死的球 快！
Kick that bloody ball. Come on!
快 现在踢 踢！
Come on, kick it now. Kick it!
- 踢！- 小伙子们赢球了吗？
- Kick it! - Are the lads winning?
你好 教授 在印度玩的怎么样？
Hello, professor. How was India?
喔 你们知道那种科学会议是什么样的
Oh, you know what these scientific gatherings are.
舞女啊 美酒还有派对
All dancing girls, wine and parties.
现在发布警告！重复一次...
东京千代田区
东京都内发布台风 暴雨警告！请大家尽快避难！
- 有困难么？- 是的
不知道大家都在避难吗？请快点去避难吧
- 请走好 - 谢谢
你在回家的路上吗？
我刚出办公室
你不是说一小时前离开公司了吗？
- 你还在喝酒吗？- 怎么啦？
这是什么呀！
- 喂...- 怎么了 没事吧？
喂？老公！没事吧？老公！
昨天 诺娜莉飓风的危害震惊了天气专家
The fury of Hurricane Noelani stunned weather experts yesterday...
以从未见过的风力横扫了群岛
...slamming into the island chain with a cataclysmic force never before witnessed.
气象学家认为这是有史以来最强大的一次飓风
Meteorologists already believe this to be the strongest hurricane ever recorded...
你就不能接一下吗？
Are you gonna get that?
这肯定会造成巨大的人员伤亡
It will surely leave a wake of death...
嗨？我刚看到萨姆微积分只拿了个Ｆ
Hello? I just saw that Sam got an F in calculus.
我注意到了 杰克 我也接到了一份他的成绩单
I'm aware, Jack. I get a copy of his report card too.
萨姆是全Ａ的学生 他从来没有不及格过
Sam is a straight-A student. He doesn't fail classes.
现在我没空谈这些
I don't have time to talk about this now.
喔 也许你应该抽点时间
Well, maybe you ought to make time.
对不起 我可不是那位一会儿就一走几个月的人
Excuse me, I'm not the one who's away for months and months at a time.
我只是不明白
I just don't understand.
我会让他解释给你听的 你能明早送他去机场吗？
I'll let him explain it. Can you take him to the airport in the morning?
- 萨姆要坐飞机？- 他参加了学校百科知识问答队
- Sam's getting on a plane? - He joined the Scholastic Decathlon Team.
- 他们在纽约比赛 - 萨姆参加了问答队？
They're competing in New York. Sam joined a team?
- 是 我想是因为有个女孩参加了 - 喔
- Yeah, I think there's a girl involved. - Oh.
我说 你能不能在早上八点半来接他？
Look, can you pick him up at 8:30?
我要走了 今晚要值班
I gotta go because I'm on call tonight.
你别晚了 我不想让他再去乘出租车了
Don't be late. I don't want him taking a taxi again.
好的 行 我会去的 我会到的
All right. Okay. I'll be there. Okay? I'll be there.
今早气象部门的会议被安排到第四层Ｂ室
This morning's weather staff meeting has been moved to level four, room B.
国家海洋及气象管理局
杰克？
Jack?
我知道你喜欢找碴
I know you're good at rubbing people the wrong way...
但是为什么 为什么你要激怒副总统呢？
...but why would you aggravate the vice president?
因为我十七岁的儿子知道的科学知识都比他多
Because my 17-year-old kid knows more science than he does.
可能的确如此 但是你十七岁的儿子不控制我们的预算
Your 17-year-old kid does not control our budget.
- 谁管他恨不恨你 - 我儿子不恨我
- Who cares if he hates you. - My son doesn't hate me.
- 我说的是如果雷蒙德·贝克撤掉我们...- 喔 糟糕！
- You miss the piont, what I'm tring tell you is If Raymond Becker pulls our budget...- Oh, shit!
等等 你...？杰克！
Wait...Will you? Jack.
喔 天啊
Oh, my God.
- 对不起 来晚了 - 爸爸 出租车已经来了
- I'm sorry I'm late. - Dad, the cab's already here.
没关系 我来处理
That's okay. I'll take care of it.
- 什么？- 给你
- What are? - Here you go.
我不生气 我感到失望
I'm not angry. I'm disappointed.
- 你想听听我的解释吗？- 这怎么可能有两个解释？
- Do you want to hear my side of it? - How can there be two sides?
我答对了期末考试的每一道题 斯蓬勒却判我不及格
I got every question right on the final. Mr. Spengler failed me...
- 只因为我没写过程 - 为什么不写？
- ...because I didn't write the solutions. - Why not?
我心算的
I do them in my head.
- 你告诉他了吗？- 告诉了 他不相信我
- Did you tell him that? - I did. He didn't believe me.
他说既然他都不能心算 我肯定是在作弊
He said if he can't do them in his head, I'm cheating.
胡扯 他怎么能因为你比他聪明就判你不及格呢？
Ridiculous. How can he fail you for being smarter than he is?
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
你这么说了？
You did?
- 他怎么说？- 他判我不及格 记得吗？
- How'd he take it? - He flunked me, remember?
喔 是的
Oh, yeah.
萨姆 对不起 我太早下结论了
Sam, I'm sorry. I jumped to conclusions.
我会给他打电话和他谈谈
I'm gonna call this guy and have a word with him.
我们会把这搞清楚的
We'll straighten this out.
嘿 你不能停在这里
Hey, you can't park there.
别担心 萨姆
Don't worry about it. Sam?
萨姆
Sam.
帕克 这里是休斯顿
Parker, this is Houston.
卡那维拉尔角这里天气很糟糕
We're seeing some bad weather over Canaveral.
看来你们这个礼拜回不来了
It doesn't look like you're coming back this week.
你老婆肯定要跟我发牢骚
Your wife's gonna give me an earful.
收到
Roger that.
嘿 来看看这风暴云团 太大了
Hey, come take a look at this storm system. It's enormous.
你还好吗？
You all right?
他害怕飞行
He's afraid of flying.
我没事
I'm fine.
据统计 飞机因为湍流失事的几率...
Statistically, the chance of a plane going down because of turbulence...
小于多少？十亿分之一？还是百万分之一？
...is less than, what, one in a billion? Or is it a million?
- 我记不清是...- 闭嘴 布莱恩
- I can't remember if it's a...- Shut up, Brian.
听着 萨姆
Listen, Sam...
别理他 好吗？没事的
...don't pay attention to him, okay? Everything's fine.
他们还在提供饮料呢
They're still serving drinks.
朋友们 可能飞机在下几分钟里将会有点颠簸
Folks, it appears we're gonna have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next few minutes.
请系好您的安全带 把面前的餐盘合好
Please fasten your seat belts and put your tray tables...
然后在座位上坐好 直到我们飞过气流为止 谢谢
...and seat backs in their upright positions until we get through this. Thank you.
喔！
Whoa!
抓住 小心！
Grab it. Watch out!
萨姆？
Sam?
萨姆
Sam.
能松一下手吗？
Can I have my hand back?
我真不敢相信我要和妈妈单独在一起两周
I can't believe I'll be alone with my mom.
对她耐心点 她一直在盼望着这个假期
Be patient with her. She's been looking forward to this holiday.
我知道
I know.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你好 再见
Hey, hello. Bye-bye.
这种恶劣天气的成因还是个谜 虽然有些气象学者
The cause of this extreme weather remains a mystery, although some meteorologists...
相信太阳黑子是罪魁祸首 上百人失踪
...believe sunspots are to blame. Hundreds are missing...
真奇怪 有一个浮标显示海洋温度下降了十三度
This is very odd. There's a buoy registering a 13-degree drop in ocean temperature.
喔 对 是这样 那浮标那天就出故障了
Oh, yeah, that's right. That buoy malfunctioned the other day.
我会查一下附近有没有船去乔治岸把它运回来
I'll see if there are ships near Georges Bank to get it.
这个浮标不在乔治岸 就在格陵兰边上
This buoy isn't in Georges Bank. It's just off Greenland.
什么？
What?
- 两个浮标出错的几率有多大？- 非常小
- What are the odds of two buoys failing? - Remote.
现在是三个了
Make that three.
纽约市又是平常的一天 交通堵塞 十条街那么长
Just another typical day in New York City. Traffic jam, 10 blocks long.
看这里 狗狗 这些人他们的车 他们的排气管
Look here, Buddha. These people, and their cars, and their exhaust...
他们正在污染大气
...and they're polluting the atmosphere.
对不起 先生 我们已经晚了
Excuse me, sir. We're really late.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
- 我们只差两条街就到了 - 我们用走的吧
- We're only two blocks away. - Let's walk.
他们犯什么毛病了？
What's gotten into them?
不知道 他们今天都兴奋的不得了
I have no idea. They're all worked up today.
在1532年 西班牙征服者弗郎西斯科·彼萨罗
In 1532, Spanish conquistador Francisco Pizarro...
在秘鲁高地卡加玛卡城击败了印加国王
...defeated this Incan emperor at the Peruvian highland town of Cajamarca.
他叫什么名字？计时开始
What is his name? Time.
蒙特祖玛
Montezuma.
不 不 蒙特祖玛在墨西哥 不是秘鲁
No, no, Montezuma was in Mexico, not Peru.
这 好象 安塔什么的
It's, like, Anta-something.
- 安塔华帕？- 就是它！
- Atahualpa? - That's it!
时间到 请出示答案
Time's up. Correct answers, please.
乌德芒队得五分 帕合斯特学院也得五分
That's five points for Woodmont and five points for Pinehurst Academy.
下个问题
Next question.
在哪一年路易十四继承了法国王位？
In what year did Louis Quatorze ascend to the throne of France?
这里太怀旧了 如果是特别设计的话还是很有特色的
This place is so retro, it might actually be cool if it were on purpose.
是啊 看看那些讨厌鬼
Yeah, look at all these nerds.
嘿
Hey.
你看起来真漂亮
You look beautiful.
谢谢 这地方很不错
Thanks. This place is incredible.
你相信这是他们的自助餐厅吗？
Do you believe this is their cafeteria?
你第一轮答得漂亮
You played a great first round.
你也一样
So did you.
这是我的队友 萨姆和布莱恩
These are my teammates, Sam and Brian.
- 我是劳拉 - 喔 我是 Ｊ·Ｄ
- I'm Laura. - Oh, I'm J.D.
- 你的学校很漂亮 - 你想参观一下吗？
- Your school's amazing. - Would you like a tour?
当然 那太好了
Sure. That'd be great.
你能帮我拿一下吗？
Could you hold this for a sec?
可以 没问题
Yeah, sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
哥们 你遇到一个很强劲的对手
Man, you got some serious competition.
别胡说
Please.
- 我猜他还很富有 - 闭嘴
- And I'll bet he's really rich too. - Shut up.
- 哪位？- 特里·瑞博森
Who is it? Terry Rapson here.
对不起 这么早给你打电话
Sorry to call you so early.
- 没有 教授 - 没关系 什么事？
No, professor, it's all right. - What is it?
喔 我们有了一些重大发现 重大而且麻烦 是这样...
Well, we've found something extraordinary. Extraordinary and disturbing, that is.
你还记得你在新德里做的演讲吗？有关极地冰川融化...
You recall what you said in New Delhi about how polar melting...
- 有可能阻碍北大西洋暖流的理论？- 是的
- ...might disrupt the North Atlantic Current? - Yes.
嗯
Well...
我认为这正在发生
...I think it's happening.
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我们的一个流浪者型浮标记录了一个13度的...
One of our NOMAD buoys registered a 13-degree drop...
表层温度下降 我已经给你发了电子邮件
...in surface temperature. I've sent you an e-mail.
等一下
Hold on.
起初我们以为是机械故障
A t first we thought it was a malfunction.
但是横跨北大西洋有四个浮标显示同样情况
But there are four more across the North A tlantic showing the same thing.
这真令人难以置信
This is unbelievable.
你预言它会发生的
You predicted it would happen.
是的 但是不是在我们这一代 太快了
Yes, but not in our lifetime. This is too fast.
没有任何预报模型有可能...
There are no forecast models remotely capable...
预测这次的情况 除了你的
...of plotting this scenario, except yours.
我的模型是根据史前时代暖流迁移而重建的
My model is a reconstruction of a prehistoric climate shift.
这不是一个预报模型
It's not a forecast model.
但这是我们现有的最接近的东西
It's the closest thing we have.
这在此前从来没有发生过
Nothing like this has ever happened before.
至少在最近一万年里
At least not in the last 10,000 years.
就象我昨天所预测那样 加强了的诺娜莉飓风是难以想象的
As I predicted yesterday, the swell off Hurricane Noelani is incredible.
这些浪头甚至比我想象的还要大 请看一看
These waves are even bigger than I imagined. Just take a look.
- 你不该去检查一下天气吗？- 这是洛杉矶 管它什么天气？
- Shouldn't you be monitoring the weather? - This is L.A. What weather?
等等 那是什么声音？
Wait. What's that noise?
什么声音？
What noise?
宝贝 我马上回来
Honey, I'll be right back.
海岸警卫队已经封锁了海岸海滩 海浪已经变得太大了
The Coast Guard closed the beaches, as waves have grown too big for...
洛杉矶气象中心 这是汤米 我在海滩上呢
L.A. Weather Center. It's Tommy.
我有事情要忙 汤米 你需要什么？
I'm in the middle of something, Tommy. What do you need?
这里正下着象高尔夫球一样大小的冰雹
There's hail the size of golf balls coming down here.
一个低气压气团正沿加里福尼亚海岸运动
A low-pressure system along the California coast...
生成的飓风横扫洛杉矶盆地
...is creating a cyclonic system across the L.A. Basin.
- 什么？- 老板 打开气象频道
Yeah? Boss, turn on The Weather Channel.
- 我想我们得发布一个龙卷风警报 - 你在说什么？
- I think we have to issue a tornado warning. - What are you talking about?
帕穆戴尔和兰喀斯特报告风速在增强
Palmdale and Lancaster are reporting wind speeds in excess...
等我一下 加里福尼亚情况很不正常
Hold on a second. Conditions highly unusual for California.
我们正在建造一个预报模型 我们需要什么？
We're building a forecast model, we need...What?
让我们优先使用巨型计算机两天 也许是三天
Priority access to the mainframe for two days, maybe three.
- 喔 就这样吗？没别的了？- 我们现在就要
- Oh, is that it? Anything else? - We need it immediately.
我会说你疯了
I would say that you've lost your mind...
但是你这样已经二十年了
...but you've been this way for the past 20 years.
- 汤姆 这很重要 - 你要建造的预报模型是什么样？
- Tom, this is important. - What's this forecast model you're building?
珍尼特·霍卡达 这是杰克·霍尔
Janet Tokada, this is Jack Hall.
珍尼特是国家航空航天局的飓风专家
Janet's a hurricane specialist with NASA.
杰克 古气象学家 我不知道他要干什么
Jack's a paleoclimatologist, and I have absolutely no idea what he's up to.
博克 这里发生了什么？
Booker. What's going on here?
他们刚刚在洛杉矶发布了飓风警报
They just issued a tornado warning in Los Angeles.
特别新闻 在我们正准备去洛杉矶进行现场报道
Breaking news as we prepare to go live to Los Angeles.
数份报告显示这一地区出现了一些极为特殊的天气情况
Mixed reports are coming in about some extreme weather occurring in the area.
好 现在由我们福克斯的同事为您在洛杉矶现场报导
Okay, we're now going live to our Fox affiliate in Los Angeles.
- 我们现在在福克斯11号直升机报道 你在吗 巴特？
We have live coverage now from our Fox 11 chopper. Are you there, Bart?
对 我在 这些龙卷风形成的太快了
Yes, I'm here. These tornados are forming so fast...
- 巴特！- 什么？喔！喔 天啊！
- Bart! - What? Oh! Oh, my God.
利萨 你在拍吗？
Lisa, are you getting this on camera?
龙卷风正在卷走好莱坞的标志
This tornado just erased the Hollywood sign.
好莱坞的标志被刮没了 就这么成碎片了
The Hollywood sign is gone. It's just shredded.
巴特 你能看到什么？有人受伤吗？
Bart, what can you see? Is anyone hurt?
对此我不会惊讶的 损失太大了
I wouldn't be surprised. There is so much damage.
有很多人在那里拍照片
And there are people down there taking pictures.
嘿 你们在干什么？快找地方躲一躲！
Hey, what the hell are you guys doing? Go for cover!
你不能待在这里！离开这里！
You can't stay here! Get out of here!
你们正在看到的是两个龙卷风正在袭击洛杉矶国际机场
What you're seeing are two actual tornados striking Los Angeles International Airport.
等一下 看来它们合并成了一个巨大的龙卷风
Wait. It looks like they've joined and formed one large tornado.
- 汤米！- 喔 天啊！
- Tommy! - Oh, my God!
糟了！
Holy shit!
我要警告所有观众远离这里
I'd like to urge all of our viewers to stay away...
- 杰夫 你在哪？- 我在雨卡和万恩街口
- Jeff, where are you? - I'm on Yucca and Vine.
- 我在路上 - 你在电视上 你正好在镜头里
- I'm on my way. - You're on TV. You're in the middle of it.
天啊！ 喔 我的天啊！
God! Oh, my God!
你应该马上离开这里 哥们
You gotta get out of there, man.
那辆客车正好砸在保时捷上！
That bus just got dropped on top of that Porsche!
喔 我的天啊 希望车里没人
Oh, my God. I hope no one was in that car.
现在为那些刚刚打开电视的观众解释一下
For our national audience just joining us now...
我们现在正直播洛杉矶市区 汤米？
...we are going live to downtown Los Angeles right now. Tommy?
如果你看到我后面 那是龙卷风
If you look over there behind me, that's a tornado.
对 洛杉矶的龙卷风
Yes, a twister in Los Angeles.
这是那些正在毁灭我们城市的龙卷风其中之一
It's one of many tornados that are destroying our city.
那还有一个 那里是洛杉矶的地平线
There's another one. That's the Los Angeles skyline.
这真令人难以置信！ 太大了！我从来没见过这样的
It's unbelievable! It's huge! I've never seen anything like it.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
这看起来像...
It looks like some sort of...
巨大的 惊人的 恐怖的噩梦 只不过这一次是真的
...huge, horrific, terrifying nightmare, only this is the real thing.
对 我正在看
Yes, I'm looking at it right now.
对 是 发生了什么事？
Yes, it is. What's happening?
我会给你打回去的
I'll call you back.
总统先生 洛杉矶遭遇了一系列的龙卷风袭击
Mr. President, Los Angeles has been devastated by a series of tornados.
除此之外 联邦航空局希望你下令终止所有空中交通
On top of that, the FAA wants your approval to suspend all air traffic.
- 你认为我们该怎么办？- 在我们搞清楚事情原委之前
- What do you think we should do? - Until we can figure it out...
我想我们没有什么选择 先生
...I don't think we have much choice, sir.
你们现在所看到的是龙卷风过后的洛杉矶市内情况
What you're seeing is what's left of downtown Los Angeles.
嘿 哥们 我刚刚给我妈妈打完电话
Hey, man, I just got off the phone with my mom.
对不起大家 我十分抱歉 但是我们需要换频道
Excuse me, you guys. I'm really sorry, but we need to change the channel.
联邦航空局已经终止了美国所有空中交通
The FAA has grounded all air traffic in the United States.
不幸的是这道命令对这两架飞机来说来的太晚了
Unfortunately, the order came too late for two planes...
猛烈的湍流致使它们在中西部地区坠毁
...brought down by severe turbulence in the Midwest.
- 第一架...-“十亿分之一”理论不起作用了
- The first flight...- So much for "one in a billion."
好 好 听着 大家 请听一下
All right. All right, listen up, everybody. Listen up, please.
我们有很多工作要做 我们没有太多的时间
We've got a lot of work to do, and we don't have much time...
那么我们现在开始 请 沃斯亭？
...so let's get started, please. Vorsteen?
我们所有的网格模型都没有用了
All our grid models are worthless.
我认为这次网格模型帮不了我们
I don't think grid models are gonna be a lot of help here.
加拿大人报告猛烈的旋风正从北极移来
Canadians report tremendous circulation moving from the Arctic.
在西伯利亚 一个前所未见的低气压云团已经形成
In Siberia, there's a low-pressure system never before seen.
澳大利亚遇到了有史以来最强烈的台风
And Australia just saw the strongest typhoon ever recorded.
- 这些现象之间有联系吗？- 我们必须考虑这种可能性
- These things are interconnected? - We have to consider the possibility.
唯一有可能影响全球气候的力量是太阳
The only force strong enough to affect global weather is the sun.
- 国家航空航天局有什么看法？- 我们已经检查过了
- What's NASA have to say? - We've already checked.
太阳一切正常
Solar output is normal.
那么北大西洋暖流呢？那有什么关系？
What about the North Atlantic Current? What about it?
我昨晚接到了海德兰中心瑞博森教授的电话
I got a call last night from Professor Rapson at the Hedland Center.
他认为暖流已经变化了
He thinks the current has changed.
好啦 杰克 那怎么可能？
Oh, come on, Jack. How could that be?
暖流的形成取决于淡水与盐份间的微妙平衡
The current depends upon a balance of salt and freshwater.
- 这个我们都清楚 - 是的
- We all know that. - Yes...
但是从来没有人调查过极地冰雪的融化后
...but no one knows how much freshwater has been dumped into the ocean...
有多少淡水流入了大海
...because of melting polar ice.
我想我们达到了一个盐分稀释的关键点了
I think we've hit a critical desalinization point.
这可以解释是什么造成了这种极端的天气
It would explain what's driving this extreme weather.
海德兰中心有一些令人信服的数据
Hedland had some pretty convincing data.
他们已要求我将之输入我的古气候模型当中以预测今后的情况
They've asked me to feed it into my paleoclimate model to track the next events.
你是说这些不正常的天气还会继续吗？
Are you suggesting these weather anomalies are gonna continue?
不仅仅是继续 会更糟
Not just continue. Get worse.
我认为我们遇到了一次巨大的气候转变
I think we're on the verge of a major climate shift.
汤姆 你准备和管理层怎么讲？
What are you gonna tell the Administration?
你想我应该讲什么？政府现在必须作好长期性准备了
What do you expect me to tell them? The government has to make preparations.
- 杰克 你有的只是一个理论 - 给我巨型机 我可以证明它
- You have a theory. - Give me the mainframe. I'll prove it.
不行
No.
你有四十八小时
You have 48 hours.
- 霍尔教授 - 是
- Professor Hall. - Yes.
- 我认为你的理论有可能是正确的 - 跟我来
- I think your theory may be correct. - Walk with me.
就在几个星期前 我观察到了最强烈的飓风记录
Just a few weeks ago, I monitored the strongest hurricane on record.
冰雹 龙卷风 这些都合乎理论
The hail, the tornados, it all fits.
你的模型能够模拟风暴下的形势吗？
Can your model factor in storm scenarios?
- 我们没有时间 - 喔 也许我可以帮忙
- We haven't had the time. - Well, maybe I can help.
- 欢迎加入 - 谢谢
- Welcome aboard. - Thanks.
嗨 我是詹森
Hi, I'm Jason.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
你有彼得的ＣＴ扫描结果吗？
Do you have Peter's CT scan results?
有 治疗让肿瘤减小了百分之二十
Yeah. The treatments shrunk the tumor 20 percent.
- 他今天的视力好点了吗？- 不 没有变化
- Is his eyesight better today? - No. No change.
- 嗨 彼得 你今天怎么样？- 好点了
- Hi, Peter. How are you doing today? - A little better.
好
Good.
让我来听听
Let me listen here.
你能看见那上面的字了吗？
Can you read that?
不能 但是我记得图片里讲的故事
No, but I remember the story from the pictures.
是吗？
You do?
我妈妈以前经常读给我听
My mother used to read it to me.
她一定会为你骄傲的 你这个勇敢的大男孩
She must be very proud of you. You've been such a brave, big boy.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
杰克 你已经连续工作了二十四个小时
Jack, you've been working for 24 hours straight.
你是唯一一个没有休息过的
You're the only one who hasn't taken a break.
也许我该眯一小会儿了
Maybe I'll try to shut my eyes for a while.
如果你拿到结果通知我
Call me when you get the results.
弗兰克 他总是这么专心吗？
Frank, is he always so obsessive?
- 对 - 是的
- Yeah. - Yes.
他从来没放松过吗？
Does he ever lighten up?
- 没见过 - 没有
- Not really. - No.
- 你们一起工作多长时间了？- 喔 弗兰克已经和他
- How long have you been working together? - Well, Frank's been working with him...
从石器时代就开始了 而我刚做了两年的苦役
...since the Stone Age, but I've only had to endure two years of servitude.
杰克
Jack.
杰克 我们拿到结果了
Jack, we got the results.
六到八个月？那不可能
Six to eight months? That can't be.
那时间不是按月算的 是按星期
That time scale isn't in months. It's in weeks.
洪水已经造成多处设施关闭 包括林肯和荷兰隧道
Flooding has caused numerous closures, including the Lincoln and Holland Tunnels.
这所学校里的管道十分破旧 这种大雨 下水道很快就堵了
The plumbing in the school is really old. With this rain, the sewage got stopped up.
你在哪里过夜？
Where are you staying?
他们在为我们找住处
They're finding a place for us with kids here.
你肯定不能在明天之前回到家里吗？
You can't get home any sooner than tomorrow?
喔 爸爸 如果我能的话 我会的 你知道 只是...
Well, look, Dad, I would if I could, you know. It's just...
气味太难闻了 爸爸
This smell is unbearable, Dad.
别再讲笑话了！ 我想让你尽早回家
Stop kidding around! I want you home.
爸爸 我会上火车的
Dad, I'll be on the train.
帮我个忙 就别担心我了 我会处理好的
Do me a favor. Just don't worry about me. I'll figure it out.
好吧 儿子 我们明天见
All right, son. I'll see you tomorrow.
嘿 萨姆 猜怎么着？
Hey, Sam, guess what?
我们找到个地方了
We got a place to stay.
太好了
Great.
到现在为止 恶劣气候还没有袭击华盛顿 本地居民不准备冒险
So far, the terrible weather hasn't hit D.C., but local residents aren't taking chances...
人们纷纷抢购以防备被认为是...
...as people stock up for what is already being billed as...
- 有史以来最糟糕的风暴季节 - 你最好能确定
-...the worst storm season on record. - Better be sure.
- 我可是生死寄于一线 - 你看过模型了
- My ass is on the line. - You saw the model.
我希望那是错的
And I hope to God it's wrong.
- 副总统先生 - 汤姆
- Mr. Vice President. - Tom.
- 你认识霍尔教授 - 对 我们见过面
- You know Professor Hall. - Yes, we've met.
霍尔教授有些重要信息 我想你该看一看
Professor Hall has some information I think you should look at.
我们刚从模拟模型中得到了些结果
We just got these results from our simulation model.
- 他们会解释是什么导致了这样的天气 - 我等会儿会看的
- They explain what's causing this weather. - I'll read it later.
- 我必须先和联邦应急管理局开个会 - 这非常紧急
- I have to meet with the director of FEMA...- This is very urgent.
我们的气候在六到八个星期之内将发生剧烈变化
Our climate is changing violently. It will happen over the next six to eight weeks.
你说过这在一百年内不会发生
You said this wouldn't happen for another 100 years.
- 我错了 - 喔 那可能这次你也错了
- I was wrong. - Well, suppose you're wrong this time.
我希望我是错的 但是你必须意识到到处都发生了什么
I wish I were, but you're aware of what's happening everywhere.
我们已经为这次风暴做好了必要的准备 你还想我们做什么？
We're making all the necessary preparations for this storm. What more do you expect?
你必须现在开始考虑进行大范围的疏散工作
You have to start thinking about large-scale evacuations right now.
特别是北部的州
Especially in the Northern states.
- 疏散？- 对
- Evacuations? - Yes.
- 你疯了吗 霍尔？- 我必须走了
- Have you lost your mind, Hall? - I have to go.
副总统先生！ 如果我们现在不行动的话 那就太晚了
Mr. Vice President! If we don't act now, it's going to be too late.
来吧 杰克
Come on, Jack.
谢谢你带我们来这里
Thanks for bringing us here.
我不能让你们还没有参观自然历史博物馆就走啊
I couldn't let you leave New York without seeing the Natural History Museum.
当然不能 这是一个动物展览 一个个肚子满满的
Of course not. It's a fine collection of stuffed animals.
嘿 哥们 来瞧瞧这个
Hey, guys, check this out.
这个猛犸象的尸体在西伯利亚冻土带被发现它保存完好
"The body of this mammoth was found perfectly preserved in the Siberian tundra...
它的嘴和胃里还有食物
...with food still in its mouth and stomach...
说明它在吃草的时候被突然冻僵
...indicating that it froze instantly while grazing."
大雪降临英伦三岛已经二十四个小时了
It's been 24 hours now since the snow started falling across the British Isles...
北欧地区也是一样 而且丝毫没有停止的迹象
...and over Northern Europe. It shows no signs of letting up.
不 你不要再担心了
No, You've got to stop worrying. No, no.
没问题 我们有充足的补给 我们只是被雪困住了
It's fine. We've got plenty of supplies. We're just snowed in.
对 不 没关系 没关系
Yeah. No, it's all right. It's all right.
- 不 你待在那里 - 我会没事的
- No, you stay where you are. - I'll be fine.
对 我也爱你 好 再见
Yeah, I love you too. Okay, bye.
- 嘿 珍妮特怎么样？- 喔 还好
- Hey. How's Jeanette? - Oh, fine.
渡船刚刚靠岸
The ferry just landed.
西班牙一定不错 真希望我能在那里
Must be nice in Spain. Wish I was there.
一支皇家空军的精锐直升机救助队已经被派出
An elite RAF search-and-rescue team has been deployed by helicopter...
前往救助皇室成员到安全的地方
...to airlift the royal family to safety.
- 哼 你想他们会来救我们吗？- 不太可能
- Yeah, you think they'll come get us? - Not likely.
幸运的是我们自己有储备足够把船压沉的茶和甜品
Luckily we've got our own genny, enough tea and biscuits to sink a ship.
喔 我们会没事的
Oh, we'll be fine.
只要厕所没问题就好了
As long as the loo doesn't back up again.
我们的能见度为零 保持航向和速度
We've got zero visibility. Maintain heading and speed.
- 我们的航向？- 035 长官
What's our heading? 035, sir.
大约离巴尔莫罗城堡还有四十公里
Approximately 40 kilometers from Balmoral Castle.
我们看不到你
We've lost visual contact with you.
- 这块表出毛病了 - 风速降为零
- This gauge can't be right. - Wind speed has dropped to zero.
我们遇到了垂直的环状云团
We have vertical walls of cirrus cloud formations.
- 到底发生了什么事？- 该死的油管被冻死了
- What the hell is going on? - The bloody fuel lines are starting to freeze.
引擎压力正在下降 螺旋桨转速在下降
Port engine pressure is dropping. The rotor rpm is dropping.
我们的右弦熄火
We've got a flameout on the starboard side as well.
做好撞地准备
Prepare for crash landing.
使用紧急燃油
Select emergency fuel.
来呀 该死的！
Come on, you bastard!
起来！
Come on!
我要对你说的是保密的
What I'm about to say is supposed to be confidential.
几小时前 三架直升机在苏格兰坠毁
Several hours ago, three helicopters went down over Scotland.
它们因为燃油在管道内冻结而坠毁
They crashed because the fuel in their lines froze.
- 在什么温度下？- 华氏零下150度 [摄氏零下101度]
- At what temperature does? - Negative 150 degrees Fahrenheit.
我们必须查一下
We had to look it up.
气温下降的速度非常快
The temperature dropped phenomenally fast.
在地面上 人们在没爬出汽车之前就被冻僵了
On the ground, people froze before they could get out of their cars even.
- 你能给我一份两小时前苏格兰地区的卫星图吗？- 好
- Can you get a satellite picture of Scotland two hours ago? - Yeah.
我们数据堆积成山
We've got mountains of data...
但是却没有足够的计算机资源来分析它 你能帮帮我们吗？
...but nowhere near enough computer power to analyze it. Can you help us?
把你得到的数据传给我们 我们尽力而为
Send us what you got. We'll do our best.
谢谢 杰克 再见
Thanks, Jack. Bye for now.
这是气温下降时候的苏格兰
This is Scotland at the time the temperature dropped.
这情况看起来就象飓风一样
This thing looks just like a hurricane.
只是飓风不能在地面形成
Only hurricanes don't form over land.
- 晚上好 先生 - 嘿 哈罗德
- Good evening, sir. - Hey, Harold.
- 谢谢 维克托 明早见 - 好的 先生
- Thanks, Victor. See you in the morning. - Right, sir.
- 糟糕的天气 - 给我说说看
- Terrible weather. - Tell me about it.
哇
Wow.
你就住这？
You live here?
只是在周末的时候
Just on the weekends.
这是我爸爸的地方 他不经常在家 于是...
It's my dad's place. He's kind of never around, so...
他在哪？
Where is he?
和我继母在欧洲滑雪
Skiing in Europe with my stepmom.
这是你和你兄弟吗？
Is this you and your brother?
对 那时我们一起骑车
Yeah, that's when we took a bike trip together.
这样的雨到现在为止已经下了三天了
It's been raining like this for three days now.
来 快点
Come on, hurry up.
我只是站在这里
I'm just standing here.
你不能待在这里
You can't stay here.
反正我从来不喜欢这里的社区
I never liked this neighborhood anyway.
在大中心车站是一片慌乱的景象
It's a mob scene here at Grand Central Station.
有一半以上的站台已经被淹没 所有的火车服务已经终止
Over half the platforms are flooded and service has been suspended on all trains.
飞机仍然停在机场而火车现在也停止服务
With planes still grounded and trains now out of service...
这真是个坏消息
...that's bad news for the...
维克托来接我了 你们需要搭车去火车站吗？
Victor's coming to pick me up. You guys want a ride to the train station?
不用了
Not anymore.
在诺瓦斯科舌 今早在数秒中之内海浪就升高了25英尺
In Nova Scotia earlier today the ocean rose by 25 feet in a matter of seconds.
我们在几天前所担心的终于发生了
What we have feared for the past few days has indeed happened.
冷空气前锋已经从北极移动
The cold front moving from the Arctic...
在加拿大形成了巨大的风暴系统
...has created an enormous storm system in Canada...
听起来很难相信 但它看起来更象一个热带的飓风
...which, incredible as it sounds, looks more like a tropical hurricane...
我要去接我的弟弟 你们要搭车吗？
I gotta go pick up my little brother. Do you guys want a ride?
- 他在哪？- 他在费城的寄宿学校
- Where is he? - He's in a boarding school in Philadelphia.
如果这个系统移向南方
If this system moves south...
我们就将看见海啸在风力驱使下侵袭整个东海岸
...we could see a wind-driven storm surge threaten the entire Eastern Seaboard.
好吧 再见
Okay, bye.
维克托的车被堵在了第五街口
Victor's stuck in traffic over on Fifth Avenue.
如果我们能在那里和他碰头的话出城会更方便一点
It'll be easier to head out of town if we meet him over there.
你是说走去？不 不能象这样
You mean walk? No, not in this.
我们应该走楼梯
We should take the stairs.
我们可在顶层
We're on the top floor.
我猜我们得走着下去了
I guess we're walking.
也许我们应该等在这里
Maybe we should just stay here.
我认为这位小姐说得对
I think the young lady is right.
不 我们必须回家
No. We need to get home.
嘿 西斯 这里
Hey, Cesar, come here.
你在干什么呢？
What are you doing?
狼 它们跑了
The wolves, they're gone.
这只是让你们能大概了解一下
Just to give you an idea of the situation...
这里的情况每况愈下
...which seems to be becoming worse with each passing minute:
现在 在岛上的大部分地区都出现了洪水
At the moment, we have flooding in most parts of the island.
在曼哈顿大部分市区内 因为电力中断
We've got traffic snarl-ups because the electricity is now out...
交通已经瘫痪了 没有交通灯
...to almost every part of Manhattan. No traffic signals.
最少有两百起汽车事故
Car accidents, at least two hundred.
而下曼哈顿区 我们已被告知 几乎无法进入
And lower Manhattan, we've been told, is virtually inaccessible.
你能打电话给妈妈吗？你能打电话找她吗？
Can you call Mom? Will you please phone her for me?
嘿
Hey.
狗不允许进入
That dog can't come in here.
我说 哥们 外面瓢泼大雨啊
Come on, man. It's pouring out there.
我不管 看那个标示
I don't care. Read the sign.
请勿携带食品 饮料及宠物入内
这可是个公共图书馆
It's supposed to be a public library.
来 哥们 这边
Come on, guys, this way.
对不起 你的包
Excuse me. Your bad.
该死的一千五百美元的防水雨衣
Goddamn 1500-dollar waterproof raincoat.
- 请闭嘴吧 哥们 - 这里肯定到处都有很多老鼠
- Please, shut up, man. - There must be rats everywhere.
那是因为这是纽约
That's because it's New York.
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
- 开门 大佬 - 已经停止服务了
- Open up, big papa. - It's out of service.
停止服务了
It's out of service.
- 我给你一百美元 你为我服务 - 你不需要那么做
- I'll give you a 100 dollars. - You don't have to do that.
不 真的 两百美元 我不要了
No, really. 200 dollars. I won't have it.
上帝 我爱公车 这太有意思了 这样最好玩了
God, I love buses. This is so much fun. This is gonna be the bomb.
喂？
Hello?
- 我打不通司机的电话 没有信号 - 这是行不通的
- I can't reach my driver. No signal. - This is insane.
我们无法开车 我们应该回公寓去
We're not gonna be able to drive. We should go back.
- 对 我赞成 - 你开玩笑吗？我们必须到高一点的地方去！
- Yeah, I vote for that. - Are you kidding? We have to get higher!
过来
Come on.
到图书馆去
Up to the library.
冷静点
Calm down.
我不明白你在说什么
I can't understand what you're saying.
如果你保持冷静 女士 我会带你离开的
If you stay calm, ma'am, I'll get you out.
门被堵住了！
The door is jammed!
我不懂法语！
I don't speak French!
嘿 劳拉在哪里？
Hey, where's Laura?
- 她就在那里！- 她就在那！就在那 看见了吗？
- She was just right there. - She's right there! Right there, see?
她在干什么？
What is she doing?
告诉他们遮住眼睛
Tell them to cover their eyes.
有堵水墙正冲向纽约城 大家注意
There is a wall of water coming towards New York City. Everybody...
什么？她的包还在车里 他们的护照
What? Her bag's in the cab. Their passports.
别管它了
Forget about it.
我去找 来
I'll get it for her. Come on.
天啊
Oh, my...
劳拉！
Laura!
- 萨姆 - 不！布莱恩 别！
- Sam. - No! Brian, no!
劳拉！劳拉 看！
Laura! Laura, look!
过来 来！
Come on. Come!
来！
Come on!
萨姆！
Sam!
教授
Professor.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 是内维尔的大作吗？- 内维尔早就过了画图画的年龄了
- Is that Neville's handiwork? - Neville's way beyond stick figures.
- 他已经六岁了 - 喔
He's 6 already. Oh.
不 这是我第二个孙子戴维的杰作 戴维
No, this masterpiece belongs to my second grandson, David.
天啊 我真不敢相信内维尔已经六岁了
God. I can't believe Neville's 6 already.
你永远不能相信他们长得有多快
You won't believe how fast they grow.
我接到杰克·霍尔的电话
I've got Jack Hall on the phone.
他们已经计算了我们传给他们的数据
They've run the data we've sent them.
在这里
Here he is.
杰克 你能重建热力循环吗？
Jack, were you able to recreate the thermal cycle?
是的 风暴的旋转
Yes. The storm's rotation...
正在把剧冷的空气从上对流层拉下来
...is pulling super-cooled air all the way down from the upper troposphere.
但是空气不应该在到达地表前就被加热吗？
But shouldn't the air warm up before it reaches ground level?
应该是这样 但是实际不是如此 空气下降太快了
It should. But it doesn't. The air's descending too rapidly.
这是独立的事件吗？
Is this an isolated incident?
我想不是
I'm afraid not.
除了苏格兰这个 我们已经观察到了另外两个超级风暴云团
We've located two supercells in addition to the one over Scotland.
一个在加拿大北部
One over Northern Canada...
另一个在西伯利亚
...and another one over Siberia.
我们能预测出他们经过的路线吗？
And do we know their projected paths?
能
Yes.
我们之前的估计是六到八周 而这差的实在太远了
Our previous estimates of six to eight weeks weren't even close.
这次风暴将改变我们星球的面貌
This one storm is going to change the face of our planet.
这是二十四小时内的路线图
Here's a projection of 24 hours out.
这是四十八小时内的
This is 48 hours out.
这是七到十天之内的
And in 7 to 10 days...
当这场风暴结束
When this storm is over...
我们面临一个新的冰川时代
...we'll be in a new ice age.
我的天啊
My God.
教授
Professor...
是你该离开的时候了
...it's time you got out of there.
恐怕那时机已经错过了 我的朋友
I'm afraid that time has come and gone, my friend.
我们能做什么？
What can we do?
尽你所能救更多的人
Save as many as you can.
杰克
Jack...
纽约有情况
...something's happened in New York.
不 停电了 我已经在这里一整天了
No, the power is out. I've been in here all day.
- 有谁需要帮忙吗？- 这里 这里
- Who needs help? - Here. Over here.
什么？
What?
这是最后一个 好好享受
This is the last one. Enjoy it.
真贪
Greedy.
现在所有线路都占线
All circuits are busy at this time.
听着 非常感谢你能来救我
Listen, thanks for coming back for me.
那真是太勇敢了
It was really brave.
我想我该把袋子还给她们了
I guess I better return her bag.
萨姆
Sam?
告诉她你是怎么想的
Just tell her how you feel.
对
Yeah.
- 你找到你的小弟弟了吗？- 没有 服务一直中断
- Did you reach your little brother yet? - No, there's still no service.
该死的手机
Damn cell phones.
对不起 二层这里有公用电话吗？
Excuse me. Are there any pay phones on the upper floors?
没有
No, no, no.
- 不过一层半的楼道里有 - 太好了
- There are some on the mezzanine. - Great.
- 但是我想那都在水下了 - 你去哪？已经停电了
- But I think it's underwater. - Where you going? Power's out.
老式电话直接由线路供电
Older payphones draw power directly from the line.
这里将会举行国家海洋大气管理局各部门领导参加的紧急会议
There will be an emergency meeting of all NOAA department heads...
哦 天啊 我一直在联系萨姆
Oh, God. I've been trying to reach Sam.
我也是
So have I.
我试过打电话但是联系不到你
I tried to call and couldn't get you.
这里乱做一团 跟我来
It's been a madhouse here. Come on.
你敢肯定你要这么做吗？
Are you sure about this?
这能用
It works.
我喜欢那张照片
I love that picture.
对 我也是
Yeah, so do I.
是在哪拍的？
Where was that taken?
迈阿密
Miami.
喔 我在哪？我不记得那次旅行
Well, where was I? I don't remember that trip.
那次萨姆和我一起 还有我妹妹 而你在阿拉斯加
Sam and I went with my sister. You were in Alaska...
在做你的博士论文
...doing research on your doctorate.
还记得他那个年纪的样子吗？
Remember what he was like when he was that age?
每件事都要“再来一次”
Everything was "one more."
再讲一次睡前故事 再来骑一圈大马“再来一次 爸爸”
One more bedtime story. One more ride on my shoulders. "One more, Daddy."
杰克 萨姆的电话 四线
Jack. Sam's on the phone. Line four.
- 萨姆？- 爸爸！
- Sam? - Dad!
- 你在哪？你还好吗？- 我很好 我们在公共图书馆
Where are you? Are you all right? I'm all right. We're at the Public Library.
- 萨姆 是妈妈 真高兴你没事 - 妈妈
- Sam, it's Mom. I'm so happy you're okay. - Mom.
你能打电话给劳拉和布莱恩父母告诉他们 我们一切都好吗？
Can you call Laura and Brian's parents and tell them we're all right?
好 当然
Yes, of course.
萨姆 那是什么声音？萨姆？
Sam, what's that noise? Sam?
萨姆？
Sam?
发生了什么事 爸爸？
What is going on out there, Dad?
萨姆 萨姆 听我说
Sam. Sam, listen to me.
注意听我说
Listen very carefully.
不要按我以前说的向南方走
Forget what I said about heading south.
太晚了 风暴会变得越来越恶劣
It's too late. The storm is gonna get worse.
会有巨大的暴风雪 在中心有个风眼 就象飓风一样
It's gonna turn into a massive blizzard with an eye in the center, like a huge hurricane.
只是空气会非常冷 你会在几秒种内被冻死
Only the air will be so cold, you could freeze to death in seconds.
萨姆？
Sam?
- 喔 我们该怎么办？- 听我说 儿子
- Well, what should we do? - Listen to me, son.
不要到外面去
Do not go outside.
找出所有能烧的东西来取暖 试着坚持
Burn what you can to stay warm, and try to wait it out.
我会来找你的 你听懂了吗？我会来找你的
I will come for you. Do you understand me? I will come for you.
萨姆？
Sam?
- 萨姆 回来吧！- 萨姆？
- Sam, come back! - Sam?
萨姆 听到我了吗？
Sam, did you hear me?
听到我了吗？
Did you hear me?
萨姆？
Sam?
- 告诉我他会没事的 - 他会没事的
- Tell me he's gonna be okay...- He's gonna be all right.
他会没事的 明白吗？
He's gonna be all right, you understand?
我还以为你淹死了
I thought you'd drowned.
- 我们来找点干衣服 来 - 对
- Let's find some dry clothes for you. Come on. - Yeah.
你把极地装备放在哪了？
Where'd you store the arctic gear?
你到不了纽约的 杰克
You can't make it to New York, Jack.
我以前在雪地里走过那么远
I've walked that far before in the snow.
这次不一样
This is not the same.
杰克 这次不一样 露西 告诉他
Jack, this is not the same. Lucy, tell him.
我必须这么做
I have to do this.
我知道
I know.
我的手在发抖
My hands are shak...
- 发抖 - 没关系 这样
Shaking. That's okay. Here.
这样 这样
Here. Come here.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我用体温来给你取暖
I'm using my body heat to warm you.
如果你四肢回血太快的话 你的心脏会承受不了
If we let the blood from your arms and legs rush back to your heart too quickly...
你的心脏会停止跳动
...your heart could fail.
你在哪学的？
Where did you learn that?
总有些人在生理卫生课上用心听了
Some of us were actually paying attention in health class.
你觉的怎么样？
How are you feeling?
好多了
Much better.
弗兰克告诉我有关萨姆的事了
Frank told me about Sam.
我不是来劝你不要去的 但是我要你先办点别的事情
I'm not gonna try to talk you out of going, but there's something I need first.
你必须把你的结果报告给管理层
You have to explain your results to the Administration.
- 我已经试过了 汤姆 - 我知道 这次不一样
- I already tried that, Tom. - I know. It'll be different.
你将直接给总统做简报
You're gonna brief the president directly.
- 就这些了吗？- 差不多
- Is that the last of it? - Pretty much.
好
Okay.
我们还发现了这个收音机 但是我想不好使了
We also found this radio, but I don't think it works.
让我来看一看
Let me see it.
狗狗 安静点
Buddha, keep quiet.
你本来就不该来这
You aingt even supposed to be in here anyway.
来 伙计们
Come on, guys.
喔 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
风暴的基本规则是它们会一直继续
The basic rule of storms is they continue...
直到产生它们的条件被破坏为止
...until the imbalance that created them is corrected.
现在 我们说的是全球重新调整
In this case, we're talking about a global realignment.
这次超级风暴会持续七到十天
This superstorm will last 7 to 10 days.
当它结束时 冰雪会覆盖整个北半球
When it's over, ice and snow will cover the entire Northern Hemisphere.
冰雪会反射阳光
The ice and snow will reflect sunlight.
而地球气候会重新平衡
The Earth's atmosphere will restabilize...
保持和上一个冰川时代相同的气温
...with an average temperature close to that of the last Ice Age.
喔 我们能做什么？
Well, what can we do about this?
向南走 越远越好
Head as far south as possible.
这并不好笑 教授
That is not amusing, professor.
你建议他们去哪？
Where do you suggest they go?
他们向南走的越远他们就越安全
The farther south they go, the safer they'll be.
德克萨斯 佛罗里达州部分没有被淹的地方 墨西哥最好
Texas. Parts of Florida that aren't flooded. Mexico would be best.
墨西哥？也许你该去管你的科学 让我们来决定政策
Mexico? Maybe you should stick to science and leave policy to us.
喔 这办法我们已经试过了
Well, we tried that approach.
在这还管用的时候 你听不进科学的话
You didn't want to hear about the science when it could have made a difference.
你到底有什么建议 教授？
What exactly are you proposing, professor?
疏散所有这条线以南的人
Evacuate everyone south of that line.
那线以北的人怎么办？
What about the people in the North?
很遗憾 现在对他们来说已经太晚了
I'm afraid it's too late for them.
如果他们走出去
If they go outside...
风暴会杀死他们
...the storm will kill them.
到了这个时候
At this point...
他们最大的生存机会是留在屋里
...their best chance is to stay inside.
尽可能安全渡过
Try to ride it out.
祈祷
Pray.
你想他们会怎么办？
What do you think he'll do?
我不知道
I don't know.
杰克
Jack...
谢谢
Thanks...
祝你好运
...and good luck.
你也一样
You too.
我们都需要好运气
We're all gonna need it.
我们不能因为一个科学家认为气候在转变就疏散半个国家
We can't evacuate half the country because one scientist thinks the climate is shifting.
- 耽误每一分钟都要付出生命代价 - 那另一半国家怎么办？
- Every minute we delay costs lives. - What about the other half of the country?
如果霍尔教授对风暴的预测是正确的话
If Professor Hall is right about this storm...
派军队到北方只会造成更大的伤亡
...sending troops north will create more victims.
我们必须现在就开始救我们能救的人
We need to save the people we can right now.
我们在战场上也会选择性救治 这种情况很像
We take the same approach in triage on the battlefield.
有时作出艰难的选择是有必要的
Sometimes it's necessary to make difficult choices...
我不认为抛弃半个国家是必要的
I don't accept abandoning half the country as necessary.
如果你早点听他的话 也许确实没必要
Maybe if you listened sooner, it wouldn't be.
胡说 对他来说很建议一下很容易
Bullshit. It's easy for him to suggest this plan.
他在华盛顿很安全 他的儿子在曼哈顿
He's safely here in Washington. His son is in Manhattan.
我认为在你置疑他的动机之前你应该了解这一点
I thought you should know before you start questioning his motives.
我们准备执行霍尔的计划
We're going to follow Hall's plan.
- 将军 - 长官？
General. Sir?
给国民警卫队下达命令疏散整个南部
Give the order for the National Guard to evacuate Southern states.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
维维安
Vivian...
给我接我的妻子
...get me my wife.
对不起 大伙 但是我们刚好用光了所有的汽油
Sorry, mates, but we're just about out of petrol.
嘿
Hey.
有没有可能
Is there any chance...
我们可以...
...that it'll run...
用这个？
...on this?
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
那是放了十二年的苏格兰威士忌
That's a 12-year-old Scotch.
先生们
Gentlemen.
为了英国
To England.
为了人类
To mankind.
为了曼彻斯特联队
To Manchester United.
我只是...
I just...
我只是希望我能看着他长大 你知道吗？
I just wish I could have seen him grow up. You know?
最重要的是他会长大的
The important thing is he will grow up.
阿门
Amen.
也许你应该找别人帮帮你
Maybe you should have somebody help you with that.
先生 我是电子学生会的主席
Sir, I am president of the Electronics Club...
还有数学和象棋协会
...the Math Club and the Chess Club.
现在 如果这里有个更牛的人 请把他指出来
Now, if there's a bigger nerd in here, please, point him out.
我最好让你自己继续干 好吗？
I'll just leave you alone to work on it, okay?
来 狗狗 来 解决你的个人问题吧
Come on, Buddha, come on. Do your business.
看 这里没别人
Look, there's nobody around.
你知道吗？我转过去 我不会看的 我保证
You know what? I'll turn around. I won't look. I promise.
什么？
What?
嘿 哥们 有很多人在外面
Hey, man, there's people out there.
我在溜狗
I was walking my dog.
有好几百人 他们在雪上走
There's hundreds of them. They're walking on the snow.
他们去哪？
Where they all going?
他们要离开城市 要不然就太晚了
They're getting out of the city before it's too late.
好吧 所有人 安静
All right, everybody. Quiet down.
最后一个人收到手机信号是在什么时候？
When was the last time anyone got a signal on a cell phone?
我在一个小时前刚接通我在孟菲斯的表亲
I got through to my cousin in Memphis an hour ago.
他们已经开始向南方疏散了
They're being evacuated to the South.
我们也应该走
We should get moving too.
水已经被冻得足够结实 可以走了
The water is frozen over enough to walk on.
我们应该在雪太深之前赶紧离开
We should get going before the snow gets too deep.
所有人 以最快速度裹好自己
Everyone, wrap yourselves up as fast as you can.
我们不应该走
We shouldn't go.
为什么不 萨姆？大家都在离开
Why not, Sam? Everyone's leaving.
当我和我爸爸通电话的时候 他告诉我要待在屋子里面
When I talked to my dad, he told me to stay inside.
他说风暴会杀死所有在风暴里的人
The storm will kill anybody in it.
- 那你该让大家知道 - 我知道
- Then you have to say something. - I know.
对不起 先生 你正在犯一个错误
Excuse me, sir, you're making a mistake.
什么？听着 我们都很害怕 但是我们别无选择
What? Listen, we're all scared, but we've got no choice.
- 我不是说这个 - 准备好离开吧
- That's not it. - Get ready to go.
如果这些人走出去 他们会被冻死！
If these people go outside, they will freeze to death!
好 这些都是什么无稽之谈？
Okay, what is this nonsense?
这不是无稽之谈 好吗？看 风暴将越来越强
It's not nonsense. All right? Look, this storm is gonna get worse.
人在外面会被冻死
The people caught outside will freeze to death.
- 你从哪里知道的？- 我爸爸是气象学家
- Where are you getting this? - My dad's a climatologist.
- 他为政府工作 - 我们该怎么做
- He works for the government. - So what do we do?
我们应该留在室内取暖 然后等待风暴过去
We stay inside, we keep warm, and we wait it out.
雪每一分钟都在越积越厚
The snow is getting deeper by the minute.
我们困在这里 没有食品 没有补给
We'd be trapped here without food, supplies...
- 是很冒险 对...- 是不必要的冒险
- It's a risk, yeah...- An unnecessary risk.
不 不 不是
No, no. It's not.
我们已经浪费够多的时间讨论这个了 来吧 大伙
We've wasted enough time talking. Come on.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
- 听着 听着 就听一秒钟 - 来 所有人
- Look, look. Just look for a second. - Come on, everybody...
风暴正在加强 它会越来越猛烈
This storm is gonna get bad. It's gonna get really, really bad.
你们无法活下来的
You're not gonna be able to survive it.
相信我
Believe me.
先生们 请留下来 留下来吧
Sir, please just stay. Just stay.
不要...
Just don't...
她可以走了 来 直接到后面 伙计们
She's set to go. Come on, straight to the back, guys.
我们没法保持联系的
It'll be impossible to reach each other.
（你到了）在墨西哥城的领事馆留条消息
Leave a message for me at the embassy in Mexico City.
好 我会的
Okay, I will.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你 杰克
I love you, Jack.
告诉萨姆我非常爱他
Tell Sam I love him so much.
愿主保佑你
God be with you.
- 霍尔医生？- 在
- Doctor Hall? - Yeah.
我们无法联系到彼得的父母
We haven't been able to reach Peter's parents.
- 我会迟些再试 好吗？- 好 谢谢
- I'm gonna try later, okay? - Okay. Thank you.
我自己就能搬动
I got it.
你应该在向南方开的客车上
You're supposed to be on a bus heading south.
我已经照看你二十年了 你以为我会让你一个人去吗？
I've been watching your back for 20 years. You think I'd let you go alone?
这么多年我还以为一直是我在照看你
And all these years I thought I was watching your back.
钥匙在哪里？
Where are the keys?
在卡车里
In the truck.
你又想去哪？
Where do you think you're going?
你们中任何一个都不懂得导航
Neither one of you can navigate worth a damn.
没有我 你们会跑到克里夫兰的
Without me, you'll end up in Cleveland.
一路上我会尽力给你提供风暴的最新信息
I'll try to give you updates on the storm as it heads your way.
祝你好运 杰克
Good luck, Jack.
来自美墨边界的惊人消息
Breaking news from the U.S. - Mexico border.
就在半小时之前 墨西哥当局关闭了边界
Just half an hour ago, Mexican officials closed the border...
因为太多美国难民逃往南方
...in the light of so many U.S. Refugees who are fleeing south...
而这都是因为逼近的风暴
...in the wake of the approaching storm.
这些人来到这里 希望能进入墨西哥
These people came in anticipation of crossing into Mexico.
然而 他们被拒之门外
Instead, they've been met with closed gates.
现在 在一个戏剧性的反向非法移民浪潮中
And now, in a dramatic reversal of illegal immigration...
成千上万的人穿过格兰德河逃往墨西哥
...thousands of people are crossing the Rio Grande into Mexico.
在我身后展现的是一幅绝望和失望的场面
The scene unfolding here behind me is one of desperation and frustration.
人们丢弃他们的汽车带上他们的东西
People have abandoned their cars, grabbed their belongings...
非法渡河到墨西哥
...and they are wading across the river illegally into Mexico.
就是这里
Here it is.
火炉差不多有一百年没有用了
This fireplace probably hasn't been used in about 100 years.
好吧
All right.
- 你在干什么？- 你以为我们要烧什么？
- What are you doing? - What did you think we would burn?
- 你不能烧书 - 不 绝对不能
- You can't burn books. - No, absolutely not.
你想冻死吗？
You want to freeze to death?
我去找更多的来
I'll go get some more.
我来帮你
I'll help you.
我跟他们一起去
I'm going with them.
好 这里有咖啡屋或者午餐室吗？
Okay, do you have a cafeteria or a lunchroom?
只有一个职员的休息室和几个自动售货机
Just an employees'lounge with a few vending machines.
我们只靠Ｍ＆Ｍ豆和薯片不可能支持很久的
We're not gonna last long on M&M's and potato chips.
垃圾桶呢？
What about the garbage cans?
在垃圾桶里总有吃的
There's always something to eat in the garbage.
- 尼采的书？- 我们不能烧尼采的书
- Friedrich Nietzsche? - We can't burn Nietzsche.
他是十九世纪最重要的思想家
He was the most important thinker of the 19th century.
别扯了 他是个狂妄的沙文主义者 还爱上了他妹妹
Please. He was a chauvinist pig in love with his sister.
他不是狂妄的扩张主义者
He was not a chauvinist pig.
但是他爱上了他妹妹对吧
But he was in love with his sister.
对不起？ 伙计们？
Excuse me? You guys?
对了 这里有一区的关于税法的书我们可以拿来烧
Yeah, there's a whole section on tax law down here that we can burn.
在数小时的不稳定以后 交通现在又恢复了正常
After hours of uncertainty, the traffic is now moving smoothly...
从美国到墨西哥
...from the United States into Mexico.
这是因为总统同墨西哥政府达成了一个协议
This is only possible because the president was able to negotiate a deal...
以免除所有拉丁美洲国家的债务为代价 开放所有边界
...to forgive all Latin American debt in exchange for opening the border.
现在 美国的众多家庭终于大松了口气
Now, multitudes of American families are feeling a rush of relief...
露西？
Lucy?
彼得的救护车在这里了吗？
Is Peter's ambulance here?
没有
No.
- 为什么？- 他们都走了
- Why? - They've all gone.
- 什么？- 在混乱之中...
- What? - In the confusion...
我不知道到底发生了什么 人们开始惊慌 然后他们就离开了
...I don't know what happened. People started to panic, and they left...
- 上帝啊 - 有个警察带着雪橇
- God. - There's a policeman with a snowplow.
- 他在外面等着 - 天啊
- He's waiting outside. - God.
彼得除了救护车之外什么也不能坐
Peter can't be moved in anything but an ambulance.
我已经打过电话给郡救护车中心留了口信
I called and left a message for the county ambulance service.
好的
Okay.
好的 你应该走了 我留下来等
Okay, you should go, and I'll stay and wait.
露西 不
Lucy, no.
- 不 - 你应该走
- No. - No, you should go.
他不会等太久的
He's not gonna wait forever.
没关系
It's okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 没关系 - 好的
- It's okay. - All right.
你还好吗？
You all right?
我还好 我只是...我那天把腿割伤了
Yeah, I'm fine. I just...I cut my leg the other day.
你接收到信号了吗？
Did you get a signal?
是的 就一会
Yeah, for a minute.
还有别的吗？
And?
兄弟 这次到处都是风暴
Man, this storm is everywhere.
它席卷了整个北半球
It's hit the entire Northern Hemisphere.
欧洲被埋在十五英尺厚的积雪底下
Europe is buried under 15 feet of snow...
他们说这里的情况也会一样
...and they say it's gonna get just as bad here.
我是说 我想你爸爸到不了这里了
I mean, I don't think your dad's gonna make it.
不 他会来的
No, he'll make it.
他会来的
He'll make it.
白宫已经对于所有北部的州
The White House has ordered a national disaster alert...
发布了全国灾难警报
...for all Northern states.
持续暴露在风暴中是有致命危险的
Continued exposure to the approaching storm is deadly.
留在室内 想尽一切办法取暖 使用所有可能的燃料
Remain indoors and take all measures to stay warm, burning any fuel sources...
直到风暴结束 从纽约州一直到宾夕法尼亚州
...until the storm is over. Roads are impassable across New York State...
所有街道都无法通行
...as far south as Pennsylvania...
我们在哪？
Where are we?
看起来我们只走到了费城北部
Looks like we're just north of Philadelphia.
小心！
Look out!
你们怎么样？
You guys okay?
还好 还好
Yeah. Yeah.
- 再说一次 所有经过的道路...- 对不起 老板
- Once again, roads across the...- Sorry, boss.
穿上雪靴
Unpack the snowshoes.
我们从这里开始步行
We're walking from here.
来 女士 我们起来继续前进
Come on, ma'am. Let's get up and get going.
我们只到了布鲁克林 也许我们应该走回去
We've only made it to Brooklyn. Maybe we should just turn back.
为什么？半个城市已经被冻住了 没有回去的理由了
Why? Half the city's frozen under water. There's nothing to go back to.
到了起床赶路的时候了
Time to get up and keep moving.
也许我们应该待在图书馆里面
What we should've done is stayed in the library.
好了 伙计 咱们继续走吧
Okay, guys, let's get moving.
醒醒
Wake up.
你在干什么呢？
What are you doing?
隔绝热量散失
Insulating.
报纸是最好的 但是这个也可以
Newspaper's best, but this'll do.
你知道 你要是在大街上过上几年 你就会学会取暖
You know, you spend some years on the streets and you learn how to keep warm.
嘿
Hey.
谢谢
Thanks.
我想到一个
I got one.
你最难忘的假期
Your favorite vacation.
这个不算？
Besides this one?
好吧
All right.
几年前 我同我父亲一同去格陵兰进行一项他的研究
I went to Greenland with my dad on one of his research trips a few years ago...
船出了故障 我们被困
...and the ship broke down, and we got stuck.
天总是在下雨
And it rained constantly.
听起来很没意思啊
That sounds really boring.
但是实际上很有意思 你知道吗？
But actually really nice, you know?
只有我和我爸爸一起渡过了十天
Just me and my dad hanging out for 10 days.
弗兰克！
Frank!
你怎么样？
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
我只是掉下去 可以买点东西了
I just dropped in to do a little shopping.
我得把雪橇扔了
I gotta lose this sled.
坚持住！我们把你拉上来
Hold on! We'll pull you up.
詹森！你必须支撑住弗兰克的体重
Jason! You've got to support Frank's weight.
好的 我试一试
Okay, I'll try.
好的 我想现在我支撑住他的体重了
Okay, I think I have his weight now.
我正向你靠近
I'm coming to you.
玻璃碎了！
The glass is breaking!
太重了
Too much weight.
不可能支撑住的
It's not gonna hold.
不 不要
No. No.
弗兰克 我可以把你拉上来
Frank. I can get you out.
别那么做！
Don't do it!
- 不 弗兰克 不要！- 弗兰克 不要！
- No, Frank, no! - Frank, no!
弗兰克！
Frank!
你拿的是什么？
What have you got there?
一本古腾堡印刷的圣经
A Gutenberg Bible.
在稀有图书室里
It was in the rare books room.
你以为上帝会来解救你吗？
You think God's gonna save you?
不 我不信上帝
No. I don't believe in God.
但你把圣经抓的很紧
You're holding onto that Bible pretty tight.
我在保护它
I'm protecting it.
这本圣经是第一本印刷的书
This Bible is the first book ever printed.
它代表着一个思想时代的开始
It represents the dawn of the age of reason.
对我来说 文字是人类最大的成就
As far as I'm concerned, the written word is mankind's greatest achievement.
你可以笑
You can laugh.
但是如果西方文明终结了
But if Western civilization is finished...
我最少可以保留其中一小片
...I'm gonna save at least one little piece of it.
我们听说有人掉队了
We heard somebody was left behind.
- 我们带来了救护车 - 感谢上帝
- We brought an ambulance. - Thank God.
感谢你们能来
Thank you so much for coming.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你还好吗？
Hey, are you all right?
你看起来有点像发烧什么的
You look like you have a fever or something.
我没事 我只是睡不着
I'm fine. I just can't sleep.
我的脑子里全是那些没用的百科竞赛的事情
My mind keeps going over all those worthless decathlon facts.
- 很傻 哈？- 不 没关系
- It's pretty stupid, huh? - No, it's all right.
我猜你只是还没来得及调整
I guess you just haven't had time to adjust yet.
我该怎么调整呢 萨姆？
How am I supposed to adjust, Sam?
我所关心的所有事情 我所努力的所有事情
Everything I've ever cared about, everything I've worked for...
都是为将来所准备的 可将来已经不存在了
...has all been preparation for a future that no longer exists.
我知道你总觉得我把竞赛看得太重了
I know you always thought I took the competition too seriously.
你是对的
You were right.
- 那都是没用的 - 不 不 我...
- It was all for nothing. - No, no. I...
不 我只是...我那么说只是为了避免承认一个事实
No, I just...I just said that to avoid admitting the truth.
什么事实？
Truth about what?
关于我为什么加入比赛
About why I joined the team.
我参加是因为你
I joined it because of you.
嘿
Hey.
我知道
I know.
总统先生 好的
Mr. President. All right.
对不起 先生 我们不能再等了
I'm sorry, sir, we can't wait any longer.
我们是最后一队
We're the last ones.
好的
All right.
墨西卡利控制中心 这里是德尔塔26
Mexicali Control, this is Delta 26.
墨西哥 美国难民营
我们接到统帅部紧急命令
We've got an urgent message for high command.
要求优先在一区降落
Request priority for landing zone one.
收到 德尔塔26 运输机会等待的
Roger that, Delta 26. Transport will be waiting.
- 长官 - 谢谢 下士
Sir. Thank you, corporal.
- 对不起 来晚了 长官 - 继续
Sorry for the delay, sir. Carry on.
秘书女士
Madam Secretary.
雷蒙德
Raymond.
总统的车队被困在风暴中
The president's motorcade got caught in the storm.
他们没能挺过来
They didn't make it.
她早晨就没醒来 我...
And she wouldn't wake up this morning. I...
我是说 昨晚她只是有点发烧 我不明白
She only had a fever. I don't understand.
她脸色很苍白
She's awfully pale.
我们这几天都没有好好吃东西
None of us has had anything real to eat in days.
- 这是低温症 - 但是怎么可能是低温症？
- It's hypothermia. - But how can it be hypothermia?
- 我们都已经...- 也许是感冒
- We've all been in...- Maybe it's the flu.
不 不 不是感冒
No, no, it's not the flu.
你怎么知道？
And how do you know?
书除了被焚烧外还有更有用处 她有什么症状？
Books can be good for things other than burning. What are her symptoms?
我告诉过你她在几天前发过烧 她还出冷汗
I told you that she has a fever and her...She's got a really cold sweat.
她的脉搏怎么样？
How's her pulse?
- 非常快 - 她受过什么外伤吗？
- It's really fast. - Does she have any injuries?
也许是划伤引发感染？
Like a cut that might have gotten infected?
她几天前说过她的腿划伤了
She was complaining about a cut on her leg a few days ago.
我没多想
I didn't think anything of it.
喔 我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
那是血液中毒 败血病
That's blood poisoning. Septicemia.
她可能因败血产生休克
She could go into septic shock.
我以前见过 那可能很糟
I've seen that before. That can get bad.
她需要大剂量的盘尼西林
She needs a massive dose of penicillin...
或者立即使用广谱抗生素 不然...
...or a broad-spectrum antibiotic immediately, or...
不然什么？
Or what?
我从来没见过这样的情形
I've never seen anything like it.
没有参照点 我看到的全是云层
There's no point of reference. All I can see is cloud cover.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
拍摄红外线大气环流照片
Taking infrared image of thermal currents.
发到休斯顿 克罗勒夫 你的天气服务站
Send to Houston, Korolev, your weather service.
我来帮你
I'll help you.
汤姆？汤姆 起来
Tom? Tom, wake up.
我刚刚收到从航天站发来的卫星照片 你最好看一看
I just received some satellite images from the space station. You better take a look.
这个东西有多大？
How big is this thing?
中心直径为五十英里
The vortex is 50 miles in diameter.
还在增大 两个在欧洲和亚洲的云团甚至更大
And growing. The two cells over Europe and Asia are even bigger.
天啊
Good God.
这个将在一小时内袭击纽约
This one's gonna hit New York inside an hour.
詹森！
Jason!
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
詹森！
Jason!
- 你在干什么？- 那船上一定有药
What are you doing? There's gotta be medicine on that ship.
我记得你说过外面太危险了
I thought you said it was too dangerous to go outside.
我知道我说过
I know I did.
你在哪里找到那些椅子的？
Where did you find those chairs?
怎么了？
Why?
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
我也去
Me too.
来啊 该死的！
Come on, damn it!
这都是俄文 我...我知道
It's all in Russian. I...I know.
- 嘿 伙计们 我找到了 - 什么？你怎么知道？
- Hey, hey, hey, guys. I found it. - What? How do you know?
因为瓶子上面写着“盘尼西林”
Because it says "penicillin" on the bottle.
嘿 等等 这是食堂
Hey, wait. This is the mess hall.
- 我们应该能找到些食品 - 我们没有时间了
- We should find some food. - We don't have time.
听着 没有食品我们不会坚持很久 包括劳拉
Listen, none of us are gonna survive much longer without food. Including Laura.
好吧
Okay.
- 萨姆 这里 - 什么？
- Sam, over here. - What?
中奖了
Bingo.
布莱恩？
Brian?
我还好 发生什么了？
I'm okay. What happened?
我只是打开了橱柜
All I did was open up the cupboard.
我们可以利用这个把食品放在里面
Well, we can use it. Put food in it.
拉他进来 布莱恩！
Pull him in, Brian!
- 你还好吗？- 天啊 还有很多狼
- You all right? - Oh, my God, there's more.
我的腿
My leg.
来 用这个
Here, use this.
这个现在应该到达纽约了
It should be over New York by now.
卫星显示每秒钟降低十度
Satellite readings are showing a temperature drop of 10 degrees per second.
伙计们...
You guys...
我认为我们处在风眼了
...I think we're in the eye of it.
我们现在必须要回去了
We gotta get back right now.
听着 我会去外面 我来引诱狼群离开房间
Look, I'm gonna go outside, and I'm gonna lure the wolves out of the room.
当他们离开的时候 你们锁上门
When they leave, you lock the door.
祝你好运
Good luck.
布莱恩 快点 我需要点东西
Brian, hurry. I need something.
来 快点！
Come on, hurry!
布莱恩！布莱恩 打开门！
Brian! Brian, open the door!
我们现在必须走
We have to get out of here now.
布莱恩 带上给养
Brian, get the supplies.
糟糕 快走！
Oh, shit. Let's go!
拉 布莱恩！
Pull, Brian!
把药给劳拉
Take the medicine to Laura.
我们快到了 来！
We're almost there. Come on!
布莱恩！关上门！
Brian! Close the door!
不要让火熄灭！
Don't let the fire go out!
发生了什么事？
What's happening?
狗狗 离门远点
Buddha, come away from the door.
来 狗狗 来！
Come, Buddha, come!
快烧书！快烧书！
More books! More books!
我昏了多久了？
How long have I been out of it?
几个小时
Couple hours.
你感觉如何？
How do you feel?
好 发生什么了？
Okay. What happened?
我们进来的时候太急了 所以我推了你一把
Well, we had to get inside in kind of a hurry, so I sort of pushed you in.
我应该适应你这么推我的
I should be used to you pushing me around.
你醒过来太好了
Good to have you back.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
风眼已经过去了 我们离曼哈顿还有四十英里
The eye of the storm has passed, and we're 40 miles from Manhattan.
我们是不是该多等一天？
Shouldn't we wait one more day?
萨姆也许挺不了这一天
Sam may not have one more day.
你觉得我们会怎么样？
What do you think's gonna happen to us?
你指什么？
What do you mean?
我是说我们 文明 每个人
I mean us. Civilization. Everybody.
人类渡过了上个冰川时期
Mankind survived the last Ice Age.
我们当然有能力渡过这一次
We're certainly capable of surviving this one.
一切取决于我们是否能从我们的错误中吸取教训
All depends on whether or not we're able to learn from our mistakes.
我是肯定会从我的错误中吸取教训
I sure as hell would like a chance to learn from mine.
你已经尽力而为了啊
You did everything you could.
我是说萨姆
I was thinking about Sam.
杰克 你知道萨姆活下来的可能性...
Jack, you know the chances of Sam...
我对我儿子承诺过
I made my son a promise.
我会遵守诺言的
I'm going to keep it.
帕克 这里是休斯顿 你听到了吗？
Parker, this is Houston. Do you read?
收到 控制中心 继续
Roger, mission control. Go ahead.
我们收到零星的报道显示风暴正在北美消失
We've got scattered reports that the storm is dissipating over North America.
你可以确认这一点吗？
Can you confirm?
的确如此 终于开始消散了
Affirmative. It's finally clearing.
我们现在在欧洲上空
We're over Europe right now.
我近几天来第一次看到地表
I can see landmass for the first time in days.
离图书馆还有多远？
How much further is it to the library?
应该...
It should be...
就在这里
...right here.
对不起 杰克
I'm sorry, Jack.
萨姆？
Sam?
那是谁？
Who is that?
我父亲
My father.
你做到了
You made it.
我当然会做到的
Of course I did.
美国大使馆
EMBASSY OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
总统先生
Mr. President.
我收到了来自杰克·霍尔的短波信息
I've just received a shortwave radio transmission from Jack Hall.
他到了纽约
He made it to New York.
他说那里有幸存者
He says there are survivors.
谢谢 汤姆
Thank you, Tom.
那是...
That's...
那是好消息
That's good news.
过去的几个星期里让我们感到在大自然的力量面前
These past few weeks have left us all with a profound sense of humility...
我们是多么的渺小
...in the face of nature's destructive power.
多年来 我们一直以为我们可以...
For years, we operated under the belief that we could continue...
不记后果地挥霍我们星球的自然资源
...consuming our planet's natural resources without consequence.
我们错了
We were wrong.
我错了
I was wrong.
实际上我的首次致辞是在外国的土地上 大使馆里发表的
The fact that my first address to you comes from a consulate on foreign soil...
这为我们证明了世界的改变
...is a testament to our changed reality.
不只是美国人
Not only Americans...
地球上所有的人现在都成为了被我们称之为...
...but people all around the globe are now guests in the nations...
第三世界的国家的客人
...we once called The Third World.
在我们需要的时候 他们接纳和收容了我们
In our time of need, they have taken us in and sheltered us.
我对他们的好客深表感谢
And I am deeply grateful for their hospitality.
我们悼念那位逝世的领导人 他英勇的发布了疏散命令
We mourn the loss of a spirited leader whose courageous order to evacuate...
彼得？嘿 你今天感觉好点了吗？
Peter? Hey, you feeling okay today?
数天之中 我们对那些被困在北部人们的...
For days, we've despaired about the fate of the people...
命运失去了信心
...who are trapped in the North.
今天 出现了一线希望
Today, there is cause for hope.
在几小时前 我收到了消息 一小队人
Only a few hours ago, I received word that a small group of people...
在几乎不可能的情况下克服了巨大的困难
...survived in New York City against all odds...
在纽约市幸存了下来
...and in the face of tremendous adversity.
我命令一个紧急搜寻和救助小队
I've ordered an immediate search-and-rescue mission...
立刻把他们带回来 并且寻找其它的幸存者
...to bring them home and to look for more survivors.
杰克！
Jack!
- 见到你真是太高兴了 - 来 咱们上飞机
- It's good to see you. - Come on, let's go get on board.
看看那里
Look at that.
什么？
What?
你见过这么清澈的天空吗？
Have you ever seen the air so clear?